

Bogdan Sokolovskyi

SENIOR REACT DEVELOPER

sokolovskyi@yahoo.com

bogdan-sokolovskyi.github.io

+380980680706

in @linkedin.com/in/sokolovskyi

github.com/bogdan-sokolovskyi

Profile

I have 7+ years of experience working with clients on a variety of web and print projects. My expertise includes web design, including tools such as Prototype, Wireframe, Photoshop, Illustrator, Figma, and Zeplin, as well as web development, including JS, ECMAScript 2015-2021, React, Redux, React Hooks, TypeScript, MERN Stack, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, WebSocket, Lodash, jQuery, HighCharts.js, JSON, Rest API, SPA, HTML, PUG, CSS, LESS, SASS, SCSS, Bootstrap, Responsive Layouts, Flexbox, PHP, SQLite, MySQL, NG-INX, WordPress, GIT, GitLab, GitHub, Bitbucket, Docker, Bash/Command Line, Scrum, JIRA, YouTrack, Trello, Redmine, Heroku Cloud, Chrome DevTools, PageSpeed, React/Redux DevTools, Postman, Graceful degradation, Progressive enhancement and JS Tools (Yarn, npm, Webpack, Gulp, Babel, ESLint). I also have experience in Corporate Branding and Graphic Design, including UX/UI, Responsive Design, Mobile Design, and Cross-Browser Development.

As a freelance web developer and designer, I collaborate with several web developers in Australia, while also maintaining clients in Europe and the USA. I am currently located in Ukraine and am available to discuss your project over the phone or via Skype.

Professional Experience

From September 2020 to October 2022

STRONG MIDDLE REACT FRONT-END DEVELOPER

BIMP Kyiv, Ukraine

- Integrations with 1C:CRM, 1C:Enterprise, 1C:Accounting
- Integration of financial and management accounting systems (MAS)
- Development of the application code structure as a SaaS solution based on 1C:CRM
- Technology stack used in our CRM:
 - 1) Design: CRM UX/UI
 - Front-End: React Hooks, Redux advanced pattern(dynamic reducers), TypeScript, SQLite
 - 3) Back-End: NodeJS

From August 2018 to July 2020

MIDDLE REACT FRONT-END DEVELOPER

FLEXIBLE TECH AND GERCHIK & CO Kyiv, Ukraine

- Development of a personal user account with a flexible interface and a flexible modular structure
- Development of risk management tools
- Connecting and configuring charts, graphs, and controls into an interactive dashboard. Works with the Highcharts Stock Library
- Creating layout templates on the front-end framework React.JS for the CRM system
- Using react-router and advanced elements of the React.JS API
- Synchronous stream with Redux and reusing previously created components
- And much more...

About me



Married (with child)

Ukrainian

Portfolio

Some Works

bogdan-sokolovskyi.github.io

Code Skills

ECMAScript 2015-2021

ullet ullet

React, Hooks, Redux

TypeScript

SOI ite

NodeJS

HTML / SCSS / WEBPACK / GIT

• • • • • • • • • • •

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Software Skills

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Professional Experience

From April 2018 to August 2018

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

COLORISOFT Kyiv, Ukraine

- Development of HTML templates and design integration for the largest E-Learning System Web Portal, "WebTutor."
- A new adaptive design was created, along with HTML templates and scripts integration

From 2015 to April 2018

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Design Studio Vinnytsia, Ukraine

- Fixed front-end bugs (HTML, CSS, JavaScript errors (JQUERY), and PHP)
- Conducted UX tests to test the usability of mobile or websites
- Optimized pages for page speed using Google Page Speed (API) for Apache to obtain higher rankings on Search Engines (SEM)
- Made on-site SEO implementations to increase traffic to client websites
- Analyzed traffic and made necessary changes for a better user experience

From 2014 to 2015

JUNIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER

Freelance Vinnytsia, Ukraine

- Created and maintained Wordpress-based sites and templates
- Programmed and debugged in HTML, CSS, and PHP
- Modified photos to be used in websites using Adobe Photoshop
- Assisted in creating the GUI of a real estate application
- Created and executed small programming projects

2013

VOLUNTEER WORK

Web Design & Web Development

- Co-developed a vibrant, secure website using interactive features and SEO best practices to optimize traffic, page views, and the user experience (UX)
- Created online promotions, press releases, and donation forms that increased cash and food contributions from the local community by 53%
- Linked online donations to the fundraising database

2013

STUDENT PROJECTS

Web Design & Web Development

- Developed a website for a fictitious clothing manufacturer that included tools for marketing, cross-promotion, and email blasts.
 The site also included an embedded WordPress blog, plugins, and a custom banner widget to promote new clothing lines
- Created a website for a mythical pizza shop that included a slideshow and collapsible sections on the menu page
- Developed a picture viewing website for a fictitious reality company using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and popular APIs like Facebook, Twitter, and Flick. Added an XML file for captioning

Language Skills

Ukrainiane

Native

English



Intermediate 2 (B1)

Education

From July 2020 to September 2020

MERN STACK (MONGODB, EXPRESS.JS, REACT, NODE)

Online and Distance Learning Courses Kyiv, Ukraine

- Node js (32 AH)
- MongoDB, Express.js (20 AH)

From February 2019 to March 2019

REACT WITH TYPESCRIPT & REDUX: DYNAMIC REDUCERS

Online and Distance Learning Courses Kyiv, Ukraine

- JavaScript. TypeScript (14 AH)
- JavaScript. React Hooks (6 AH)
- JavaScript. Dynamic Redux Reducers (6 AH)

From August 2018 to October 2018

From August 2018 to **REACT WITH REDUX TRAINING**

Online and Distance Learning Courses Kyiv, Ukraine

- JavaScript. React and JSX (24 AH)
- JavaScript. React Router and Redux (16 AH)

From July 2013 to September 2013

PHP TRAINING COURSES

Online and Distance Learning Courses Vinnytsia, Ukraine

- PHP. Level 1. Web-development fundamentals (24 AH)
- PHP. Level 2. Web-sites development with MySQL (24 AH)
- PHP. Level 3. Professional development with PHP7 (24 AH)

From April 2013 to May 2013

WORDPRESS CONTENT MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

Online and Distance Learning Courses Vinnytsia, Ukraine

- WordPress. Level 1. Creating a Website. Content Manager(16 AH)
- Wordpress. Level 2. Creating and maintaining sites with complex structure (16 AH)
- Web-mastering. Configuring Web Servers (24 AH)

From February 2013 to November 2013

JAVASCRIPT TRAINING COURSES

Online and Distance Learning Courses Vinnytsia, Ukraine

- JavaScript. Level 1. Web-Development fundamentals (24 AH)
- JavaScript. Level 2. Extended course (16 AH)
- JavaScript. Level 3a. jQuery Library (16 AH)
- JavaScript. Level 3b. HTML5 API (24 AH)

From November 2012 to February 2013

INTRODUCTION TO WEB DEVELOPMENT

Online and Distance Learning Courses Zhmerinka, Ukraine

- HTML and CSS. Level 1. Web Development using HTML5 & CSS3 - (32 AH)
- HTML and CSS. Level 2. Cross-browser development, usability fundamentals - (32 AH)
- HTML and CSS. Level 3. Advanced methodologies and tools typesetting - (24 AH)

From June 2012 to August 2012

WEB DESIGN

Online and Distance Learning Courses Zhmerinka, Ukraine

- «Principles of design». Express-course (16 AH)
- Development and design of websites (32 AH)